The movie event that will blow their cover.
Penguins of Madagascar is a family, animation,
adventure film directed by Simon J. Smith.
Skipper, Kowalski, Rico and Private join forces with undercover
organization The North Wind to stop the villainous Dr.
Octavius Brine from destroying the world as we know it.
Skipper (voice), played by Tom McGrath.
Kowalski (voice), played by Chris Miller.
Private (voice), played by Christopher Knights.
Rico (voice), played by Conrad Vernon.
Dave (voice), played by John Malkovich.
Classified (voice), played by Benedict Cumberbatch.
Penguins of Madagascar is a 2014 American animated spy comedy
film directed by Eric Darnell and Simon J.
Smith, and written by Michael Colton, John Aboud, and Brandon Sawyer.
A spin-off of the Madagascar film series, it was
produced by DreamWorks Animation.
The film features the voices of Tom McGrath, Chris Miller, Christopher Knights, Conrad Vernon,
Benedict Cumberbatch, Ken Jeong, Annet Mahendru, Peter Stormare and John Malkovich.
It takes place after the events of Madagascar 3: Europe's Most Wanted (2012) and follows the Penguins as they join forces with the North
Wind intelligence agency to stop the octopus Dave who seeks revenge on penguins for upstaging him at zoos and aquariums.
The score was composed by Lorne Balfe.
Penguins of Madagascar was released theatrically in the United
States on November 26, 2014, by 20th Century Fox.
The film received mixed reviews from critics.
Despite grossing $374 million on a $132 million budget, the
film underperformed by DreamWorks' standards.
Along with Mr.
Peabody & Sherman earlier that year, it lost the studio $57 million.
The film explores themes of rescue, wolf, octopus, spy, zoo.
The tone is lighthearted.